Of all the Android launch devices, the Nexus 1 will
always hold a special place in my heart. That's not
to take anything away from my first Android device, the
HTC G1, that launched Android into the world with its
distinctive chin and slide-out keyboard, or the HTC Magic. First
pre release android phone I got to dog food when
I joined google. And the first, the wave of devices
we gave every attendee starting at google IO in 2009.
2010 was the year android went from that's
interesting to global phenomenon. Growing from 100,000 activations a
day in May, to over 300,000 by December.
That was seriously helped by the release of the
Motorola Droid. I can still remember the offices
here in building 44 echoing with the constant refrain
of Droid as each device rebooted. The Droid was
the first of the thinner, higher res, more powerful
Android devices that have since become standard. And it
was also the device whose release on Verizon here in
the U,S. Really kicked off the flood of Android
activations. But I was a Londoner then, and the Droid
was a [UNKNOWN] only phone, so it was never
really a device I truly used. Then, there was the
Nexus One, code-named Passion. The first device I felt was
pure Android was also the phone we brought with us
on our 2010 Android Developer Labs World Tour. Me
and my colleagues travel across the world. Seven cities
in ten days. Introducing over twenty thousand developers to
Android by way of presentations and a free Nexus 1.
As a result, I made a lot of friends
across Europe and learned exactly how many boxes of phones
I can carry across snow drifts in Stockholm and
icy roads in Berlin. Since then, The Nexus S4 and
five have each improved on what it takes, to make
a great android phone. And OEMs across the world, have
created 1000s of different Android devices. Starting with the Motorola
Zoom, which led Android's official expansion into tablets, and leading the
way for the Nexus 7 and 10. But that was
just the start, Those changes paved the way for the
Android mobile [UNKNOWN] west, to grow into what could be,
the brains behind anything, from phones and tablets, to TVs, cars
and wearables, like Android wear. It's impossible to know, what comes
next. Who knows? Maybe the next Android devices, will be Androids themselves.